Mohammed Yahya Alattas

Senior II Infrastructure Engineer

Contact

Saudia Arabia - Riyadh +966566046923 Mh.alattas7@gmail.com

Key Skills

People Management

Project Management
Virtualization
VDI
Linux
Backup
Storage
Infrastructure
Data Center
Network
Cloud

Certificates and courses

Vmware certified Professional - VCP

> Dell PowerEdge Associate - DCA

Red hat (RHCSA) "Course"

Profile

Senior Infrastructure Engineer for 8+ years, had a position managing two separate environments from infrastructure side. Deployed, maintained and Troubleshooted full Infrastructure and Data Center layers, install and configure servers and network devices. Proactively manage and maintain servers. implement project plans, risk assessments and validated UAT documents.

Experience

October 2022 - present Solutions by STC •Senior Engineer II, IT infrastructure• Saudia Arabia, Riyadh

- Mentor L1, L2 Engineers, and follow up with their technical development.
- Assess and rearchitect VMware products and underlying components (vSphere)
- Restructure and enhance VDI Infrastructure (Vcenter- AD Virtual network Horizon view VDI OS images Desktop Pools UEM AppVolume ThinClient MFA)
- Redesign vROPS / vRA (VMware Vrealize operation and automation) To integrated it with multi packs (IBM storage vCenter Horizon Dell OpenManage and Cisco).
- Configure and implement "Ansible Automation" and fulfill automation scenario "Playbook".
- Install and configuring RedHat OpenShift and migrate 3 Applications to containerization environment
- Evaluate new projects based on the Company KPI.
- Documentation all infrastructure, systems, and processes. To create Knowledge Base.

February 2019 – September 2022

Confidential "SBM" • System Administrator • Saudia Arabia, Riyadh

- Configuring, Patching and Administration of VMware products and underlying components (vSphere)
- Implement and Operate VDI Infrastructure (Vcenter- AD Virtual network Horizon view
 VDI OS images Desktop Pools UEM AppVolume ThinClient MFA)
- Install and configure vROPS / vRA (VMware Vrealize operation and automation) and integrated it with multi packs (IBM storage – vCenter – Horizon – Dell OpenManage and Cisco).
- Installation and configuration of Linux Redhat servers." SAP installation severs and maintain specific SAP packages from RedHat for SAP ".
- Manage Backup System (IBM Tivoli "Linux Based") creation and update of the backup policies and responsible for SAP Hana Backup using HANA Studio.
- Managing SAN switches (Brocade) Status, Configuration and troubleshooting the issues.

- Manage and administrate two types of environments (Internet facing and Air gapped) from Infrastructure side (HW-Virtualization-OS-Backup-Storage and virtual networking)
- Data Center analysis layer one (Devices Connections –Enhancement Plan)
- Installing Dell HW server (Power Edge), Configuring RAID controllers, Implemented Dell OME (Dell OpenManage) and Dell OMPT (Dell OpenManage Power and thermal) Monitoring Tools.
- Administrate and manage patching management solutions for full corporate (RedHat Satellite Desktop Central BIGFIX) following CR process.
- Multi-vendor management, Negotiating, Establishing SLAs, ensuring contracts are in place to support the provided services.
- Create and review various types of documentation (BoM, Capacity Plan, CR, Improvement Management Report, IT Budget, POC, LLD, UAT, HLD, etc.)
- Monitoring servers, network, and applications using (IBM Netcool Vmware vROPS ManageEngine OPmanage)
- Good experience in security systems, like firewall, anti-virus software, Multi factor authentication systems (Imprivata OneSign ManageEngine MFA), log management (IBM Qradar Splunk), content filtering proxy. DDos protection and Honeypots (Attivo). and involve with security Dept. solutions and new security tools and cross-domain Projects (Data Diode EDR Sandbox etc.)

September 2015 – February 2019

Elseif contracting construction company • System Specialist • Saudi

- Installing and configuring Windows Servers (Domain Controller DHCP DNS File System)
- Cisco Meraki SD-WAN installation and integrated with the HQ
- Installation a full Network, from the antenna tower of ISP to The End User point
- Installed IP meetings System and Handles the Meeting over the Internet. (AVAYA, 3CX, Call Manager)
- Configuring and migrating MS Exchange from on-prem 2016 to Office 365 cloud Service
- Documented technical side of the project
- Presented and Training IT Employee
- Responsible for backup (Acronis and Veritas)
- Work with ERP Team to support their system (Oracle Cloud ERP)
- Monitored Antivirus for end users and Firewall rules

Education

Jan 2015

Bachelor of Computer Engineering • Umm Al-Qura University • Makkah, Saudi Arabia